The...going down I think my microphones on
and we ready to go all right we're ready to go hello, welcome, welcome I'm
thrilled just absolutely thrilled to be here talking to you about nano server
...server is by far.
The most important most significant change we
have made in server sense windows
and t so put your seat belts on kind of just show you
this fantastic new server...is a cloud optimized server on
...snowbirds I'm a distinguish engineer and I'm the lead architect for windows server
and system center datacenter and joining me are management same principle pm
and windows server now here's the thing to realize all this work
here's the man this guy has been working on this so long you can really how
...about...years ten years now seriously we've been doing this at
various stages it's taken the combination of ten years worth of effort
...the whole thing...
Is just...been twenty-year okay so ok so let's go ok, so, first of course a
valuations make sure you fill out your valuations we do pay attention of those things off, you know,
where that we do we read all the comments and we respond to
their we react to them...make improve based on
...so here's what we're...we're going to start off talking about
what we hear from our customers and we're very customer focused
...will talk about our server journey and then our cloud journey
then we'll get into some of the details about nano server show you some very
preliminary results these a preliminary results some of the numbers we have not which be
clear...very early days with...server we have not
done a performance pass ok so some of these numbers
will get better we're not done refactoring so some of the
numbers might get a little worse I will also tell you that as we do this we're looking
and saying hey maybe we should make corresponding changes to the other versions of our
...persian and the other versions of server as well ...preliminary results
will tell you about...status our road map and then actions for you guys to go do
...also point out this talk is the developer focus talk
ok next week
...ignite we're doing a similar but different version of this talk focused in
...there's a bunch
of additional content that will be released in that talk so, what you want
to do is you want pay attention that talk in particular we're going to be releasing a lot
of our demos as videos on channel nine and we'll show you that coming up
...so what we've been hearing from our customers really there's
...big buckets three of them are on this slide so...cinepak my business why do I have to
patching reboot something that's not being used on my servers one of reboot is required I want my
machines back-up and servicing my customers as fast as possible and server
images are too big so they take up too much space on the disk it takes a long-time to installing configured
takes a long-time to reboot takes a long-time to predeployed over the network
...infrastructure requires to many resources so my server operating system is using a lot of resources
...I could be on...reselling to my customers
or could be providing more services within my organization and,
the by limiting the amount of resources the operating system uses I can also increase my
vm density or run more containers based on your container functionality?
The other area where we've really been hearing a...around security having more things
installed things that I don't need obviously opens up...vectors for attackers and
...headlines over the last year so all the different attacks that
...major corporations and the second one from the bottom is pretty interesting,
you know, someone hackers are attacking manufacturing companies now and actually causing physical damage
their equipment within their plants...bowie sometimes we kind of customers have this idea of like
gold image with a install everything on it and then they give it to everyone and say, yeah, just ignore the
...you'd want...if you're one of those people stop it that's a terrible idea
don't do that so really what we're hearing is customers want just the components they need
and nothing more so let me installed just the pieces I need for the services I want to
run that system don't give me like every sort of big
gold image that has all of windows server installed on it when I just need a small subset.
Ok, so, let's talk about our server journey so when we started here windows,
windows nt, you know, really that we didn't draw distinction between what a desktop was and what a
server was right and the joke was we took a desktop and kind of
...flipped over on its side in fact marker
...you may not have heard of him he's an engineer that works at microsoft anyway, so,
this guy name micros innovation fact was the guy who was became famous because he was the one
that discovered hey there's only a different...between server and client
is a registry key if you change into this you can get a server and...microsoft changed it
...about hey now is this value so they played cat-and-mouse for a while but markers the guy
that discovered that at the time that was a great thing when the world was all about I want
up to this server and...want to manage this server it was great worked
out fantastically...is nice easy to managing cetera however admin
...on servers are poison...heroine jan for
...probably feels pretty good but you do...a bunch you life goes...you do-too-much
you dad okay now...right so why is it wired admins on
gooey so horrible and the answers this invariably,
invariably when you have a local admin gooey
on a server you put the business logic in the
gooey and you call private api...now what that really means is you don't
have a good proper management api and you can't
do remote management and you can't do automation so as long as the world
...I have my server I walk up to that server and I do it the
distinction is fine local gui
for fantastic but that world was a long-time ago now it's about
datacenters now it's about agile development in the cloud and these local
gooey...poison okay so want to get the local
gooey off so we started that really in server twenty-eight where we said hey now we have the
...server core it doesn't have...sonnet at that point was separate
installed server core or full server and we made some mistakes with this
right warm particularly clear about what scenarios really work well
...version one we didn't have...full and complete management story we
didn't have a lot of the features and roles running at when we first started
of course that got fixed and really nailed it in windows server two thousand and twelve
and rtwo we had improved our management story all the interesting
roles and features are running on server core and you can choose server
core or server with the gooey and if you made a mistake you can go back and forth and
that was important because some of our ecosystem still had products that required to
...to install and then you could take the
...off and it would run just fine?
So, now that's great now we talk about our cloud journey
...so with our cloud journey here's the thing the understand in the context of measure.
Patches are very disruptive right if I have the patch the host in ensure
...measure doesn't have live migration
so if you patch the host guess what.
Every vm needs to be restarted talk about business impact
that's business impact next is hey you may or may not
...turns out as you're pretty large really large
...lots and lots of server's we take a large number servers and you say well
hey each one of those os is consumes a bunch of resources a bunch of resources times a bunch of
...that translates to a large number clocks of course taking these large images and moving
around the network consumes a lot of bandwidth that we'd rather be serving
further people now as, you know, windows server has something called cloud
platform solution comp platform solution is...a box one to
...racks so here we have live migration it's fantastic right so if I have
the patch the host got no service interruption right you will
...the m from one machine will patch that host will move them back and,
iterate...ok button a for...system...thousand vm
...to gigabytes each that means I'm live migrating sixteen
terabytes of data sixteen terabytes of data across the network that should
otherwise be servicing customer needs so even well I don't have
service interruption I still have a pretty large service impact
sorting getting at here is that the cloud really can't withstand
these interruptions right so ultimately what we concluded was that we needed a server
configuration optimized for the cloud no means literally we
need server configuration optimize
...the cloud I'm pretty sure you needed as well but I know that we needed.
And, that is what...server is yes so now...our next step in
...journey so what is a new head...sixty four-bit only deployment option for windows
server so back to jeffries comments about...being poison on
the server it is have those there is no local log on a local interface to it
there's no res intuit so you cannot terminal server intuit you have to
...fully remote we'll talk about that it's more detail is sixty four-bit only again alps
...the footprint and is part of windows server so there's a deep refactoring focused on a claudio
...infrastructure and new-born the
...applications that's worth pausing here would be really precise
where early days and now server this is version one effectively and
...focused in on these two scenarios and these two scenarios...
And, overtime oracle or focusing on these two for now and we're following the
server core patterns what that means...separate installation option...server core was back in twenty eight and
...rtwo so you have to make a
...deployment time if you're going down the...announcer...server core orserver with the
admin tools of course we're learning some of the lessons we learn from server core
...being precise about the...were after the benefit of that is I can go to you
and say hey you're part of scenario I need you to stop what...doin' and do this work and some
...as...and talk-to-you-later right so it allows us to focus in on that next
as we dramatically improved our manageability story...about that and,
we're working with partners and improve the developer story of...core has co-training how could I forget that
...for-you so, as far as now server rules and features go we've
moved two-zero footprint model so if you're familiar with windows server windows
client today when you install it there's a side-by-side folder all the optional rules and features lives
...all taking of disk space on your servers...your virtual machine images with nano server
we've removed all that so...packages for the roles that you can install you have to
install those as part of your deployment process so if you later on go to install role
on the system you have to go off and find the bits to actually install it is not on the machine
...does everywhere that right so if you notice you go into a server you say hey I'd like to have
is installed and it doesn't say please insert the
media and the reason for it is when you installed
...stuff we installed everything within install we made everyone put everything
on-disk and...staff on the side so when you say a
one install it we just take it from the side and we bring it in gate that is not how
nano server works that's one of the reasons why the images got so very large?
To the...and features retiring for the cloud os scenarios and the...the
...applications or hyper v storage server and clustering to us for your
host os and then for your app platform dearborn...outfit
...the course clr which talked a little more...five and the paths framework.
And, then we do have full windows server driver support so-if you have a piece of hardware that
you have a windows driver for that same driver works...same...stack same everything
...so you don't need different drivers for nano...you have entomol were
built-in so defenders included in announcer image...that's all versions of
server noun...with...email were on by default.
And, we are we don't have like...said we're still early days in this
for making progress here we're still working on bringing in the system center...so we're working on the
...and operations manager and working to bring
...abs insight and some of the other agents for the microsoft products as well as
regional to isv to make sure there software works on nano server.
All right so now let's talk about
that management of nano server okay so the model here is we want to
eliminate the idea of you ever sitting in front of a server managing...
gone don't do it really have this configuration you do all you configuration
to desire our shelled desired state configuration and,
you do all the remote management through core our shell notice that in say our
shell core our shell much that into wi in
...you want to integrate into the...apps tool chains in the
Develops mindset said we want to be able to manage
servers like cattle not paths.
And, the old days...me...in all days
...treat servers like perhaps right you give it a name a precious name and
you get sick you cared forward...you tended to
...with cattle you don't give them names so you give them
numbers when they're sick you fire
...the barbeque right just a completely different model okay and
you really focused in on the heard not any individual that's the way you want that's
really the cloud model okay so you want to develop this dev
...mind-set net is so if
you developing products you really want to get that model in focus is
not about getting a saying up and running and keeping it running it forever.
Ok, so, now let's talk about visual studio release management
...for familiar through visual studio release management great dev...tool.
They can get the audio.
To bananas of the...having question interesting.
We...look at the capabilities up...a lead to...and
...studio on bank tuesday in order to...and you...to
bananas the ...he...question...coit hardcopy which
...and take it into videos to the on the thematic is to
...for this...using the
...preview feature in julius...you on the team as...the
...and looking...the same to on.
The relieve...light...to get environment before hitting the production
...in each of them are
...up our...task is use is executing the deployments
...against the docket...the...the new...and we inspiring to finish.
The easy to the...environment is now
...brewer companies manager the...manager...this
...to rely on the development and...and
...second day...what...boy that's been created in
...and lots of bug in the background for the
...to where...and...to...the currently running
...debugged...the...input the...that you...
...the...that and you re he's...
drink an automatically for this particular...
This happens...the being...
Italy's dictation...
On completion of the being.
With...dot and making...when I can
...manager goals and updates the
...on the...david...and...do now.
...school.
...that...one-hour a day on the
...a...by the...to...
All rights which you saw there was visual studio release management so it's a dev
ops mindset right you build your product you put it into a released managing
pipeline words tested it's deployed through automatic systems use desired
state configuration management when you have a...you just do that again notice and
no-point...somebody...dp into a server and, bring up a gooey right now let's think about
this why is that right so imagine you go and provision a system use say...a
...like five hundred clicks later you got your system.
And, now you gotta do it to a hundred more
servers like are you really going to get five hundred mouse clicks done in the same order
...hundred times answer no way right so that's why you want
to automate things you want to script things so that hey if you get it wrong just go change
the script get it wrong changes script get right great leave descriptive alone
because you got a right and do it over and over and over and over again high-quality dev
...operations with visual studio release management so I
mention to you that...our shell core our shell and not
our shell what is the difference the differences that our shell
is based upon dot net and corporate show is based upon the
...clr so just as we have refactoring full?
...we are refactoring our shell
...our shelby to run on the course...it has the full our
...language right the compatibility remote ing
so invoke command works expressions work new our shell session new enter
ps session all that good stuff works most of the engine components are there
the one significant engine component that's not there is windows workflow that's
ok because
windows workflow can run on another machine and still manage
nano server as a managed element through the magic of our show remote
...that's directly integrated into the model support all the different our
...command...types so csharp command loads script command let's and
...commandments thing to note the
csharp commandments work if you have the underlying support for
in dot net remember you do not have the full net you have the
core clr...dot net core I think we're now calling it so,
if you're commandments called gooey staff and...to work on...server?
Most of the manageability commandments don't do that and
we're starting off with a limited set a command let's and moving very rapidly.
So, the earlier point about the...being poison and
server core being a first step at this we heard the feedback on server core that
there's a lot of things where people still have to...into the server because our tools and only run locally
there's configuration you can only do locally so we're doing a lot of work to change that go through core our
shell as well as we're developing a set of remote server management tools so these tools are
...web-based and the
designed to replace all the things that you would normally need to login locally or...
t into a server to do today so everything above-the-line we have working today we have
...remote task manager...registry editor we have...viewer of device manager we have
as configure familiar with that that's the initial configuration from server core so
that sort of overlaps with some of the control panel pieces we have some
...networking today remotely so all of this is available as a remote...manager
servers if you...not doing the automation for your herd of cattle yes but
way you definitely want to see this we're currently don't have there's so
much talk about we don't have time to show all this stuff this is one of those stunning
demos because uses the measure portal framework so,
we're definitely in...that ignite and it's definitely going to be on channel line afterwards you'll want to
put up bookmark in your calendar and go watch this stuff because you'll be
stunned is wonderful...you but whenever I think however I hear web...I think...
compromise now this is not this will blow you away and the great thing about this is
jeff mentioned earlier running...locally a lot of times you have private api
is your business logic built into those gary's on this case this is all layered on top of...on w
...getting additional w my providers put into the product and they're both in nano servers also
...server so in addition to be able to use this new ui
...of system you can scripted all using our...you could write your own tools the interface with this and
...your own gary so we're separating that out and doing
at the right way doing it the right way.
Element cloud application platform side of things like I said we're focus on the born in the
cloud application sports so we do have a subset of
...thirty two so some existing when thirty-two apple run on...server I'll talk more about
that server-side the course clr paths asp dot net five.
And, it will be available everywhere so you can...your host
...hundred physical...if we go there it's worth just like pausing and letting that
sink in so nano server is a version of windows server
okay so it's api compatible all the api is in annals server
...the same api...and full server...just fewer of them api
...put things on the desktop they don't exist so
...we serve replication shouldn't be doing anyway so that's fine
lesser replications will just run fine sometimes you might have to refactoring
to use the version that's in nano server versus something that's in the desktop version
...be clear about this is a version of the windows server, you know, when...
And, it will be available everywhere so you can deployed...your host os on your physical
machines for your hyper v host restores...
It you can run as...os in a virtual machines...is p dot net or course
...apps it will also be the base os for both flavors of containers
...windows server containers as well as a high privy containers.
We are working some futures additions so powerful desired state
configuration is not actually in the build is going to go out as part of building and working
package management which used to be called one get and we're also looking at adding additional roles
application frameworks as we...journey through to releasing windows overview next, yeah, so,
the desired state configuration will follow shortly just
a timing issue and if you're not familiar with that this thing we used to call one get
until some guys decide best...of those okayed...so,
then we ended up with powerful package manageranyway, so,
...manages a wonderful tool it allows you to go on any machine and say here the
here's the software that I would like to get running on this machine and they will find it various
repository and you can
just declare which repository you trust and which ones are on trusted and
...pull something from...repository we ask about it you can set up your own
repositories with your definitive software libraries and them say put things there and go to
machines and say install this we just find it...it's wonderful, wonderful stuff?
Ok,
so, let's talk about the server application development ok so now the question is...I'm
...developer and I...get the server thing in focus and now you bring
up this nano server like how do I think about and then the question get a lot is like so do I
coda containers are going to source code the...server
or do I have to choose it's actually a very simple story ok so here's the
model what we're doing is a deep refactoring of the server
okay we start off with nano server that's the core elements
on top of that is server now we call the server core
...a missteps in this is the server because the other thing we used to say
usu server core and there was something...call full server that...like a good thing right you
...a server application services all why require full server you're like wow you
must be great...create that men we tried to be clear about in the last version we said well
no it's not full server its server with a gooey...we want
to get even clearer the future name is going to be client?
Okay, because that's really what it is a client stack running on a server...that's
werner's...head that's what is to clients background on a server now there are times when you
want have a client stack run on a server when are those the...is remote desktop
raw desktop is a client stack running on a server so they're left definitely
legitimate cases for this but most server applications should not be used in
...client stack on a server at all ok so the model is going to be
that is a developer I code to
a server or nano server...bring up visual studio and I'm going to pick these, you know,
...just say I want mail server one full server.
Your nad...code to the client...not for-you server guys
...the client guys go put that on a client...server.
Next so developer targets server for compatibility or nano server for
...optimization and then they hit f five they get
...now they have to deploy the expedia run it and here's where it
becomes very simple you pick which one you wanted server now server you get your
exes venue deploy it on a physical server
Or...container windows server
...hyper v container okay so it's very simple story.
A server and nano server
are set of api and components and then they run somewhere they run on a
physical machine they run out of virtual machine they run a container that's...
And, one thing to point out there this that the client-server does not run in
the container neumann physical virtual thank you that's one of a container, yeah,
so, we've been pretty pointy here so, if you
get a server application that uses some of those
client api is the ain't running containers so stop that practice.
Okay,...now we got a...somehow here we're going to show you is asp dot net five
running the music store demo running a nano server the key things to point out
here are how much stuff is running today nano server pretty,
pretty great and this...also remote debugging basically
...application running on server...a
...samples point of information which sales community
...online...basic site administration user signing and
showing cut functionality being...below that...framework and
...stuff on the...modern and response user interface...I'm going to the
And,...the store see...available albums and...my
Next I'm going to...another algal.
Behind-the-scene the...database...using...framework.
Once they have moi.
...check-up.
...bigger...many...providers including microsoft
leader google and facebook and even though not sure...over ninety
...directory...demo I'm going to...using...
One...ask...information.
Once the
...information is field in I...
To not have to advancing...order.
Builders...the...grossing distort...
Now I'm going to show...can do by the speedup as five
Using the video studio debug.
I have already started...on server machine and overly music
...solution video studio also...great
...canticle...method.
Disabilities executed one
...register first...anymore process.
...daisy...environment...process holding
diminished application on server machine I...imagine question.
Now the...attached I'll go back
...start...and try to create and user.
For...will be eight-and-a-half bashes...visual studio
...experience thanks is to locals...
Modules...
I can samoa.
I can step in the code.
And,...change information...fusion point.
It is shady debugging course
...application...what is the different and debugging...
If you'd like to know more...store application you can
...call...is iness...
Great so there you saw asp dot net we have we had signal are we at any framework where
the model view controller access to all sorts
of authentication systems all running on nano server en a very
rich graphical remote debugging experience ok so now server doesn't
mean no gooey now server means remote gooey.
...talk some about
the developer experience for now server so for those of you that try to get your code running on server core
...a great experience there you have to go to a...webpage and msdn that was the api is that
were supported and it was painful there were some.
Unclear areas where what was
...not...really taken a different approach with nano server so we've fully integrated it.
...the windows sdk...that comes out with windows thing client you'll financial server
...there we've got...as a target in visual studio twenty fifteen so there's a template in
the gallery that you can go download that will allow you in visual studio target now server and actually see
...using is supported on server.
So, we have a ridge design-time experience fully integrated...the...template you get full
...so if you're using api that's not sporty you'll get a little
red errors squiggles underneath it and we have full remote debugging experience...dot net debugging experience there
you have a full debugging support through visual studio we have
a demo showing that running as well.
This is a quick look at the...server developer experience first off
we're introducing downloadable project template that will pull indirect headers in libraries so
what you can get first-class and thousands...google support when developing...server application.
Note that
any implication that from the server will automatically run inserter core hateful server.
Once ukraine...server application project you'll see the landing
...helpful f.
For example, you see that...rhythm support
...so you want to select x sixty-four from the...target.
For this...going to use...existing aman simple and
...against them the samples called accessing ramon computers.
Once we copy and paste the gone into the visual studio enter
...the main function with underscore tv notice the
cools depends on the wire-tapping library...to our products.
Right...on the product...solution explore and select property.
Go-to laker input additional dependencies click edit
...wiretapping.
Let's go on locally without any...
We see a list of register providers.
Now that's sort of...server she we already have a server machines running
...vm...prepared the partial...in the partial icy.
...copywriters to session parameter to copy our executable and symbol
pharma pd file to remote data server machines see test folder.
While...comedy ip address before we switch back to visual studio.
Now we need to teller project about herbal...
Sabrina product properties again...to debugging remote windows
debug are and change the working directory
...working directory using the ip address.
Change the remote command to randomizer replication
...see in the working directory.
Change the connection type to remote with...
authentication and change...survey to the ip address.
After we set...reporting...five to start verbal debugging session.
For the purposes...the demo already started...on...server machine.
The burger...to...point immediately notice the updated...the locals window you can
...set watches and continued warming exactly as you would in the...case.
That's type in get...version in full.
And, we see that only the x versions of api or support.
If we try to use...api by removing the x,
for example.
We immediately get...quot.
In this demo we columns of the
...developer experience started with a project template
in tennis sense and aris google support all we to a full-fledged remote of
our...have a first-class developer experience to write some really cool tools
Thanks for now if you notice that so you start off with...template picked and
...server project games full support for that when you produce the axes university
...into our shell and he did copy so we've updated our
shell so now you can do file copies from and
to remote computers so that was something use highlighting here.
I don't know if you pick up on one of...commons early on about piling the
q if you target nano server your same code will run on server core and,
server so you can create one executables that
...run anywhere in the server family.
So, he talked some...the different versions of the api
is so as we've talked about you nano
...deep refactoring so we removed a bunch of dls that provide higher-level
...needed in...server but we've had to do is pull some a gis...those so there's some
combination guys are used by a lot of apps when we looked at the varies roles we want to run on
...some of the applications we want to run on it for api is that lived in some of those things we remove that are needed
...nano server...pulled those down and put those in the new dls so what we've created are
set of reverse...so if you already have a set of code that runs
...record today is that...within the boundary of mammal server that...run today on
...nano server sort of reverse order does is it puts a version of
...ll...nano server so when you're code load it looks like that
dls available now server when the api gets called...for
...the new location where the api actually lives in nano server you don't have to
necessarily recompile against nano server if your code is already within the boundary of
...so this provides a...to get up and running quickly on server with existing code so
you when you run with reverse order will happen is the api calls are going to succeed if that
...within...boundary or you'll get a return toto of
...error not implement so, you know, that a...nano server now we're still doing a lot of
work with reverse orders so...additional a...we're going to keep pulling down so
the to build of windows server that's coming out soon doesn't have all the reverse order worked
on it the next technical preview after this formal have even more of that but if you are working with your
total national server and you come across some api is that you think would be useful to have
a reverse order for there's an email address at the end of the presentations send
us that list of api as we can keep working...factoring getting the right...functionality...server,
yeah, so, it's worth pointing out how we develop now server so we did was we started
...the very smallest component that could run and then we did was we
pick the scenarios that we wanted to run and then we figured out what api need to be re
factored to support those scenarios and then we did the next scenario and the next
...next scenario that's why we're so clear about the scenarios
the version one supports
clot os infrastructure clustered high provides a cluster storage born in the
cloud applications esp net etc.
As you go and take your applications and get them on nano server as you
encounter problems we'd like to hear about it so we can decide hey are those part of the
snares we want to focus on version one and if so then we'll find out those api
...an will refactoring them if those are scenarios that
were not targeting for version one will say perhaps later put in the backlog
in the backlog yes so that's one of the big differences with server core announcer
with server core we try to play and plug into everything that existed out there
...ecosystem of windows server with nano server with a much harder line say we've got this dividing
line only certain things are going to be functional...when I'm just going
...stuff and just to let it play with what exists today.
So, two-point-one...reversed orders is they do not eliminate the need for to
refactoring to for nano server
...hiv doesn't exist in now server and it's not something we can refactoring bring in
...going to have to adjuster code to jeffries...recalling something that
parts of a message box that's never going to work nano server and you'll have to changer code.
...the reversed orders
...optional package so...not...by default but if you do need to run something that
...and hasn't been recompile for nano server an adjusted to where the dls
...now are the...positive now you can installed them in your
...image when you get national server and upcoming windows...you'll seepackages folder that has
a reverse orders package in it and what we have today is this list on the screen so...
higher-level function either often has common api for like file and registry and things like that
...you may need for your apps even running on a small footprint server like nano server?
And, we've done a bunch of work.
And, experimented with a variety of things is...is one of low-rent
off I know screwed up...you can about all right.
So, here's the thing we mention...in the...applications we talked about
...net has et cetera that's just the beginning we want to support
all the language run...if people are writing...applications in a
language runtime those the ones that we want to support so we're doing that were actively
working that so here's what runs today many of these with the reverse...but
here's what runs once today and we...about...skill...and...dot net five-one
spar check this out okay so we've got chef.
Chef...uses ruby...got php we have engine...python
...js go read this...my sequel open ssl java
ruby sequel light and we just that list will continue to grow
this is very exciting very exciting so if you're writing a cloud os
...application and there's something you...some language...
not here let us know because we want to support that thanks again this is
...reverse...install if you just take announcer image and don't include refers folders a lot of these aren't going to
...okay,
so, again, I mentioned cloud os applications part of that is the
...tool chain earlier we showed you a demonstration of visual studio
release management that microsoft's develops tool
chaining chef is another great partner that has a develops tool chain so let's
show you that run nano server each seatbelts on right okay good?
But, what really...desktop?
...thanks for...suffer appreciated a what.
You...I...el servers fast zing
...awesome aspect of...running on I want to know resumes
...moi model we can be writing recipes like endemol
...a open-source...like jingle python and will
...recipes and make sure we get chef working on answer
...your support totally candlelight microsoft information for sign
...excellence...
Hello, everyone
...great...shut integration management running...nasser.
...use your simple build with the jingle...being more than
using engine acts as a reversed proxy server...recipes
...jingle engine x and python which as, you know,
is what jingle runs up we start using partial rewarding...internet server machine?
What changed...show sixty-four...rama chef client?
That's just go ahead and ask for this...and...whatever.
...we do I need...copyright address and thanks...explorer and...
This is assume ...manage...or integrator sample.
After entering might potentials...answer carjust because...
Let me look at the jingle recipe prevent I'm going to leverage archdiocese
...feature editing...files.
The same and chef recipe can be used on the
...systems and within continuous integration workflows to the only
...to various past and staging environments.
That's it and...sure early demo you so I'll show and therefore
ruby general iphone and engine...all-round on them server.
This server maybe nano...science but certainly notin our thanks for watching
...you go so now again woody highlighted there was our
shell has now the ability to do remote script editing
in remote script debugging again to support well, it where
you find is that as we modify the system to support nano system
mail server it makes the rest of our
system better in the same way that when we went and focused in
an be decide we've become a great enterprise server that was at a time when, you know,
somebody said that the defining user experience of the desktop was something called the blue screen of death
okay but our work on the server
...last time you saw blue screen a death right they happen but they're pretty rare and why is
it was because our investments in the server benefited
...desktop show to our investments
in the cloud are changing things so that they will benefit I benefit
the enterprise scenarios as well like full...full remote all right?
So, before, before we go onto installation...very closely reshuffle
not demo actually found some api...we moved down from up above into the reverse
orders to get everything working on there and you may have noticed...on some of the earlier
...is everything sixty four-bit so...do have to make sure...four-bit to
...announcer so if you do find things that are sixty
...api...that...down please let us know and we'll take a look at those so installation
on server and we saw that cool...but...does not have
msi support has a lot of...dependencies is not available so in today's builds
the installation options rx copier files over and manually
do registration...custom powerful scripts and we are working on installer for
national server so you can package up your code and be able to install it and we're
looking at supporting install on install inventory and both online offline installation of code.
So, the sporty task we're going to have...for files
...creatively folders...files
set permissions hormones will have services support...configure start delete.
...docom register and...register.
Was for registry so create and delete registry items and will also support integer
...that registration which is a custom action...today so focused on the
scenarios we believer needed to install code on nano server but again if there's functional in here that you need to install
...these for this normal-looking and just be clear
...distinction between installation configuration turns out
that a lot of the problem is when you get those two things confused you want
to install something and then you want to
...those different things and you can start using this or x copy and then
you can figure out with things like desired state configuration directly?
So, talked about a lot of stuff at all sounds very exciting
...mention we talk about some preliminary results these early numbers again things may change
as we keep evolving the system and some of the things we refined and make better
...may make server core better as well which would be...but,
some of these numbers may change so how are we doing with all this stuff
we're talking about so first is we're going look at servicing and this is all the patches
released during twenty fourteen software
...available throughout the year of two thousand fourteen how to compare with
server core and the server with aggression just be clear we did decode analysis of every single
...fourteen and then we...to the code base and said does that code base
existent nano server so basically we did the right way there's no gamesmanship
going here so now server would have...nine important bulletins compared to...
for server core and twenty-six for full server so critical
bolton is even more interesting it's only two critical bulletins for
a whole year for nano server so record eight...around...
To this and...the number of removes three routes holier.
So, record had six full
server would have eleven so you would have only been able to skip one month's worth of reboot so you can see that greatly
increases your up time and we still want to do some more work we really want to get those to a maximum of to reboot
...year fernando server.
The security side so the...we haven't done a lot in this area it's slower seventy-three compared
...ninety-eight.
...services running twenty-two versus forty-six so a little less than half.
Ports open twelve versus thirty one's a little more than a third
...significantly reduce the number of services imports those attack
vectors that all those hackers we talked about earlier love to try and access.
Resource utilization so process counts twenty-one versus twenty six
...hundred-fifty megabytes versus two hundred fifty five megabytes
we actually have a nano server on old tower machine...booting in fifteen seconds.
Kernel memory...sixty-one megabytes version hundred
thirty-nine about half that's less than half my friend I know.
So, deployment improvements this is very interesting along with
the patches so from starting the deployment process to fully provisions
...accessible...the network nano server forty seconds that so in the computer
and indeed api to address up and running and accessible server core took five
minutes so we also have a set-up and it's a demo that will get up on channel nine...
night of...including announcer machine and this onto old tower machines will
hundred megabyte switch now server takes three minutes to deploy from starting
...you process to upping fully provisions and that's on...hundred megabytes which
was some old hardware...a datacenter environment you'll get that even faster.
We did the same thing with server core the same equipment nineteen minutes so the
nano server time actually if you we've done some analysis a lot of times actually spent topping
...over so we gotta do something there but.
And, this footprints this word is really so now servers
four hundred megabytes compared to almost five gigabytes for server core.
Wait for it and then on the bhd five there's a little bit overhead...the
...you can...goes from four point
eight six-point-three announcer goes from four hundred four hundred ten so great
improvement in footprint back to the commons were making earlier about the smaller installation size
...faster reboot all of that were...there,
yeah, so, what I like to tell people at this point is you just saw those numbers pretty
stunning numbers the next time you have somebody and developer and admin say well, you know,
I really don't want it seen convenient to learn our shell I really don't like local
remote gooey ways think back at these numbers and then look at that person and say?
Is that person really worth four times as many
...that much extra resource consumption and that much extra
time and...answer might bs?
So, now server windows overview next will be...installation option much like server core.
Will not be listed in setup with nano server you do
while the ways we get so small is you have to put the...and there's no plug-and-play
are user mode plug-and-play and nano service kernel mode so it's not going to often detect what
drivers are in our what...required for...particular hardware you have to inject the
drivers in the image before you...rather than showing up in set-up and if you haven't put the driver
...basically installing a brick it is a separate image that you have to customize before deploy
...was in a separate full-grown media and under that there's a packages some folder in
...there...oem...package so-if you...all the...available server core and just put that big blob
...you can do that or you can customize and just pick the...specific your hardware and have a
...small and tight image it will be available next server released been released
...as part of ignite and build and
...follow-on technical previews so we're going to get a guide upon technet on how you can work with
...server how you can do not management through powers overloading and all
the information on how to inject...and...so...all coming,
yeah, and, it's worth again remind mining you that were very early days with
nano server so when you get edge, you know, you're going to have to read the released
...and have some struggles but we'll have some fa...out there some video demos but,
obviously each release are become more polished?
Okay, so, the roadmap so nano server is the future of windows
server.
Version one
we're starting focused in on these cloud scenarios okay and then, you
know, there's...server and is born in the cloud applications but,
it's really the foundation for all the components going forward we want
a model of just enough os so if you
...an application...you need five gigabytes...a...great
...of five gigabytes exponents but shouldn't have ten and if you only want
nine hundred megabytes...have nine hundred megabytes so you'll see that claudio
and net nano server starting off with the cloud scenarios is a
first step to a fully compositional factored operating
system where you get the components that you want and we'll keep moving rolls over to
...server so if you have particular roles are important,
... we're collecting feedback...to prioritize what we go after next after hyper
...and file server so you just the things you want as long as you want the right things?
That's...don't require during exactly as long as it doesn't require
...ok so we do have server core and that will run your existing
enterprise applications for now and again both of these
your run these you can decide which one you want to target and then you run it
in a physical in a virtual and container thanks pretty simple storing.
Okay, so, the actions re target your code for nano server
it's the future you want to get on this you want to get on this we think people are going to adapt this pretty
quickly saw the numbers right they are compelling they speak for themselves as I
mention this is the most significant change we have made to the server
sense windows nt so you want to get on this bandwagon and help us right tells where we
...so deployed let us know what encountered any problems that
you have here's the thing and, you want to shift to
for remote management...I know some of you have not done this.
Embraces remote management that
is the future full stop and you should do both for nano server
injure other products it's the only way our customers
are mutual customers can adapt in scale
right can automate can improve their ip so,
do that here's a great...resources how we do
...a...minutes left okay we had we...one demo for the and...
Because we weren't sure we're going to have enough time so this is our...we
...nano server running as a vm instance in
measure and we then robo use remote our shelled
...this all these videos...on channel...this afternoon and more will come after
...at the end of the demo will show you the channel...should see it however long
...server...on the cloud and...this them what I'd like to
...some overpower shows whom features running on the server once of
...might be m I use the dashboard to
locate the public ip address copy the clipboard.
And, pieces into...powers...less store that...in two-dollar.
I also need to create a social object using nucleus session and
...has the computering as well as the administrative credentials.
This social object is going to come in handy throughout them.
For starters...remote into the
...server...using entropy ascension.
I use their...that we have a social object classroom dollar.
...change folders to see test and
mature and find absolutely nothing there so we...are session
and check out our local partial folder and fining...script
...obvious one using ps edit to edit.
We take a look at it doesn't do
much of its useful but this is just a
...let's take a look at...feature copy item
...too numerous to session and from...let's
use to session to copying that local tests
group over to the remote...she.
Saw the path one-point-two local para and destination is a see
...machine will also copy from session from order
...session...for that we use the copy of these which is
...for copywriter and half of this case is actually the remote
the windows locks doesn't log parable coming to the local folder.
So, let's...dirt and we actually find that this amar has made this
journey cthree over let's now entropy ascension again.
And, see if
...local...has actually made it safely to the remote
...and...office.
Once we run...we actually find that id...but
...w my object produced error...string.
Is actually truncated so let's look at the next
...feature which is editing remote files isp edit credit
...scrap?
Not only converters the rules for...we can actually be bomb them
...variables...set of...by...
And,...script again using...
...stop at the break point and I have full access to the command-line
...the first thing I do is get...
Get...object and...demean errors not
...the avi command.
For that I realized that get w my object is not
support on server instead I should be using gets.
So, a press...five to stop the burger.
And, replace might get the object commended...get
some instance and press of age to test out a current I.
Now I turn my attention to the truncated...and I said
another preprint inside the loop and present five again.
...actually realized that I should not be adding plus three two-dollar.
So, I...five.
Fix that line that was an easy fix.
And, run...again this...actually ran successfully.
This than we ran...server...vm...answering the cloud and use partial
remotely and several partial school new features to copy files from and
...will machine as well as edit and debug...scripts.
...for watching all
right to last items I'm number one is the channel
line channel nine if you search channel line and
...nano server you will see the nail server a channel and we have
four videos up there I think a couple more will show up in a few minutes and you can watch all everything you
saw here again next week we're going to release a bunch more that are more it pro
focus will definitely want to watch and some amazing stuff number two if you like
this session please fill out the evaluations remember my name is
geoffrey snow over if you didn't like the session please fill
up the evaluations remember my name is mark...of...just fine my name and
...all my sessions so thank you very much for your time and ...